# Shuai Zhou

#### **UX DESIGNER**

I'm a UX designer with 5 years working experience in building enterprise and consumer software products. I'm currently employed as UX Designer for digital design user experience team in AT&T. I am responsible for delivering solutions to AT&T clients. By collaborating with product owners, designers, and developers on daily basis. Over the years, I have acquired a solid expertise in several project management methodologies and built up experience leading agile teams. Authorized to work in the US for any employer but need sponsor in the future.

# **Education**

Harrisburg University of Science and Technology, Harrisburg, PA

01/2017 - Present

Master of Science in Project Management

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

08/2012 - 12/2015

Master of Design in User Experience Design

Hubei Institute of Fine Arts, Wuhan, China

09/2007 - 06/2011

Bachelor of Art in Textile Design

# **Experience**

#### UX DESIGNER in AT&T, Dallas, TX

01/2017 - Present

Worked in the Digital Design User Experience Team, I worked closely with the Product team in an Agile/Scrum workflow to design visually-compelling and highly-usable web applications for a B2B Internet Service management product, AT&T Business Center. The product were used by all AT&T's business clients.

- Lead user interface & experience designer for AT&T Business Center application for Web.
- · Organized, tailored, and moderated local and user testing sessions based on personas and use cases.
- Designed mock-ups for product team to show how our applications would look if integrated into the systems.

#### UX DESIGNER in TourConnect, Frisco, TX

04/2016 - 12/2016

As the only user experience designer in TourConnect worked with development teams to develope the user personas and user journey in order to enhance functionality and usability for product. Gathered requirements from clients and conducted focus group to discover user needs. Create user-friendly and highly-usable web applications for a Service management product.

- Designed an engaging online tour industry community platform with an experience modeled after leading-edge e-contract tool and community sites, combining social interactivity with e-commerce conversion.
- Delivered high quality design docs: sketches, sitemap, user flows, wireframes, mockups, specification.
- Helped define product features; built interactive prototypes for demonstration.

#### UX DESIGNER INTERN in Hospital Communications Inc, Cincinnati, OH

05/2015 - 09/2015

As a Internship UX designer on the Hospital Communications Inc (HCI), I was leaded by VP of sales and worked with the development team to redesign the health care TV application. The application applied on all Hospital Communications Inc TV products.

- Conducted user research through interviews and usability testing before and after the re-design
- Created intuitive design flows by high fidelity wireframes and clickable mock-ups.
- Designed, built, and tested interactive prototype to iterate and evolve design concepts of the project

#### UX/UI DESIGNER in Sohu Inc, Beijing, China

12/2013 - 12/2014

As a user experience and user interface designer for the mobile design team at the Sohu Inc. Worked with the design team and development team in an agile development environment to design mockups and wireframes for applications and websites. Created interactive interfaces by working with developers to ensure an application adheres to the Sohu User Interface Style Guide (UISG) and is user-friendly.

- Prototyped visual design concepts and friendly interactive to provide solution for mobile applications, resulting in a better user experience.
- Produced flow charts, wireframes and designed page layouts for the mobile application.
- Created and documented patterns for visual systems.
- Responsible for designing and developing mobile web pages in a fast-paced environment.

#### GRAPHIC DESIGNER INTERN in Michelman, Cincinnati, OH

05/2013 - 08/2013

As a graphic designer worked for Marketing department in for Michelman Inc. Designed and produced catalogs, sales sheets, proposals, scenario illustrations, brochures, posters, custom displays for trade shows and in-house exhibits and all other items.

- Actively researched industry trends to bring new ideas and applications to company.
- Collaborated with marketing personnel in development of product information.
- Created sales collateral, marketing literature and print ads.

# GRADUATE ASSISTANT in University Of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

01/2013 - 12/2015

As a graduate assistant worked with Associate Professor Renee Seward in the See Word Reading App. See Word Reading® is a personalized, fun & effective platform for students to learn early literacy skills through a suite of two applications a teacher app and student app.

- Gathered user data through methods such as participatory user interview, user testing, and analytics reporting and utilized that data to identify and prioritise Pain Points.
- Developed sketches and wireframes for teams, introduced new tools, Sketch App, to enable effective online collaboration and deliverables.

# TEACHING ASSISTANT in University Of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

08/2012 - 12/2013

As a teaching assistant worked with Associate Professor Fernandez Oscar in the Design History Course.

• Developed trust and rapport with students, provided assistance to teachers and engaged students in learning activities and positive behaviors to optimize their understanding of lessons.

### **Skills**

UI/UX design, Interaction Design, Motion Graphics, Visual Design, Illustration, Prototyping, Wireframing, Storyboards, Style Guides, Visual Mockups, Responsive Design

# Link

http://shuai.design/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/shuai-zhou-898729b2/

# **Additional Information**

TOOLS & PROGRAMMING: Adobe Creative Suite, Microsoft Office, Sketch, InVision, Axure, Lucidchart, Zeplin, Jira, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery.

REFERENCES: Upon request.